WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
You can't live like this another year.
Tommy, you've never even
seen Arthur's kid.
Nor John and Esme's.
I'm staying with Polly.
She's in a bad way.
I'll get through to her.
The union convenor
causing all the trouble,
her name's Jessie Eden.
I will conduct myself as a businessman...
Who says "sweetheart"?
Today, everyone in the family
received one of these.
Changretta knows where we all live.
We need to be together at a place
even they won't dare to come.
You mean back home?
This is the New York Mafia
we're talking about.
And we're the Peaky Blinders.
We're not the Peaky Blinders
unless we're together.
- And what's the purpose of your visit?
- Pleasure.
Please, can we get some help here?
Please? It's all right, Michael.
It's all right, Michael.
You're going to be OK.
Don't leave us now. Just keep breathing.
No. No.
I don't want fucking kids
in here. I want soldiers.
who joined us for the sport.
All right. Get out. Go on. Go.
- I want men who served in here.
- All right, Pol.
God, please, don't take my son.
Mrs Gray, please.
- Please, don't. God, don't take my son.
- Pol.
Pol. He's in good hands.
- God, please, don't take my son.
- Polly.
Pol? Pol?
Damn, fuck those bastards responsible.
All right. Let them do
their job, all right?
Let them do their job. I'll get soldiers.
I'll be back. I'll be back.
Is it him?
Yeah.
On his own doorstep.
His own fucking doorstep.
All right, get out.
And you, out.
Poor John.
Fucking John.
"In the bleak midwinter..."
We promised, Arthur.
No, I can't...
In the hole, we promised.
I can't look at him...
Come here, brother.
Come here.
Come on, come here.
Oh, man.
Now, say it.
Say it, brother.
"In the bleak midwinter..."
You're cursed, and I curse you again!
And again! And again!
- Esme...
- No!
Come on. Come here. Come on.
Leave me with him.
You've spoken to him.
Now it's my turn.
Arthur.
No peace for either of you...ever.
Our stuff will stay with me.
I'm taking the children on the road,
to live with decent people.
They'll never know the
cursed side of this family.
We're done with them, John.
Tommy, they're gathered.
John is dead.
Esme has gone on the road with the Lees.
She's taken the kids.
Michael is badly wounded.
They say it's 60-40 in his favour.
There's no number, there's no percentages.
There's only the hand.
The hand beneath him stops him falling.
I spoke to someone.
My son'll live.
Michael and John were shot
because we killed someone.
Vicente Changretta.
His son, Luca, has come to take revenge.
Men from New York and Sicily
here in Birmingham.
These men will not leave our city
until our whole family is dead.
That's how it works - an eye for an eye.
It's called vendetta.
The bullet's been written.
It says "LUCA".
When the time comes...
..And it will come...
..He, as the oldest brother...
I will put this bullet
into his fucking head.
There's been some bad blood between us.
Polly, please.
Until this business is settled,
we stay together...
..And we stay here.
Small Heath, Bordesley,
Hay Mills, down to Greet.
We know every face and every
man is a soldier in this army.
These men are professionals,
they're good at what they do,
so we're going to need more than we have.
I've sent a message to Aberama Gold.
No.
No, Tom.
I'll get you 50 Lee boys. Good men, Tom.
I don't need good men, Johnny.
For this, I need bad men.
Tommy, his people are fuckin' savages.
You know? Heathens, Tom.
They don't even let them in the fair,
so they come and steal our horses.
You know, stealing from their own, Tom.
So this the plan, Thomas?
This is the plan?
A bullet with a name on it,
help from a bunch of savages?
We're going to go on the offensive.
I've spoken to Moss.
- Moss!
- I've spoken to Moss.
Moss is putting out word...
..Eyes and ears so we can find 'em.
Yet the truth is, the police
are busy with the revolution.
Moss says they're expecting strikes
and riots when the weather gets warmer.
The Bolsheviks are planning...
The Bolsheviks couldn't plan
a fucking picnic.
- He's reading the wrong papers.
- Ada!
Real or not real, the coppers
don't give a fuck about us.
All right?
Which means...
..That here today, in this room,
we have to agree to
end this war between us.
Take a vote.
Peace.
I was never a part of this, but...peace.
Shut up, Finn.
Why can't I say "Peace"?
Arthur, let him have his say.
Finn, sit at the table.
Little bastard.
They're sending us fucking kids,
Sergeant Major...
to do men's work.
My son's not here to speak...
so I'll speak on behalf of us both.
Truce.
Five for peace, two for truce,
one abstention.
Let's get on with the war.
Curly, here we are.
Here, catch.
Right. Right, move them, boys.
Unload, unload!
Hat.
Blues and Villa goalkeeper?
Dan Tremelling plays
in goal for the Blues,
and Tommy Jackson for the Villa.
Fair enough.
- Charlie?
- What is it, Curly?
We've run out of bullets, Charlie.
We need more ammunition!
More ammunition!
Johnny, more ammo.
We're like sitting ducks
here, if the wops come.
Yeah, well, Tommy said
we should do it in the open.
This is how John wanted to go.
On the smoke.
But the truth is,
we died together once before.
Arthur, me...
Danny Whizz-Bang,
Freddie Thorne, Jeremiah, and John.
We were cut off from
the retreat, no bullets left,
waiting for the Prussian cavalry
to come, and to finish us off.
And while we waited...
Jeremiah said we should
sing In The Bleak Midwinter.
But we were spared - the enemy never came.
And we all agreed...
That everything after that was extra...
And when our time came,
we would all remember.
You remember that God spared you.
But what did you do with
the extra time that he gave you,
eh, Thomas?
At ease. At ease.
Do not return fire!
I repeat - do not return fire!
Stand down.
The men doing the firing are on our side.
I took the trouble
of getting an invitation to Aberama Gold.
Oh, fuck. Now it's begun.
You put us out in the open on purpose.
You used John's funeral
fire as a fucking beacon.
- We were never in any danger, Polly.
- You set a trap.
Finn? Finn?!
Go to the yard and light the fires.
You set a trap with us as fucking bait.
Who's dead?
Our enemies.
- Who's dead?
- Want to know, Pol?
Two fucking local Italians
heard about the vendetta,
tried to make a fucking names
for themselves - that's who.
We got word to them about the funeral
the where, the when.
Told them where to stand for the best shot.
And Aberama Gold will do the rest.
That's the language of vendetta
they take one of ours,
we take two of theirs.
You used your own brother's funeral.
When did we vote on this, Tommy?
Curly, get a boat ready to
take the bodies to the city,
and another boat for anyone...
anyone who wants no more part of this.
Cos this is how it's going to be.
Polly!
I'm not staying for this, Arthur.
I'm going home.
Oh, yeah. Home's 57
Watery Lane. You go there...
Lock the doors, you wait for me.
- Key to number 57.
- I'm going home to the country.
You will stay here until it's over.
Take the fucking key, Linda.
Look, away from here, you
are a weakness to all of us.
They will take you hostage, and the baby.
They will use the baby.
Take it. Put the kettle on.
Wait for your husband.
The only way any of you
Shelbys will leave this place
is on a cloud of smoke, like John.
Well, you're a Shelby now, too, Linda.
500 each, 1,000 for the brace.
Where do you want them?
Charlie, take them to the yard.
Not too far, not too deep, Curly.
We need the message to get through.
OK, Tom.
Finn, you go with him.
Go on. Go with him.
Oh, Tom? Tell Johnny
to save me some goose, please.
On your feet.
Wait outside.
Hello, Mum.
They said you'd be out cold.
No, don't move.
The doctor said they'd
sewn you up like a football.
What else did he say?
He said you took four bullets.
Only one was live.
One was a ricochet...
...Two were already spent.
Two had passed through John.
The last thing I remember was his face.
I watched him go.
Where's Tommy?
Oh, don't worry about Tommy.
Just get better.
Where is he?
Tommy's back.
We're all back.
The Garrison, Watery Lane, Charlie's.
I need a cigarette.
No.
I've made a decision.
- Give me a cigarette, Mum.
- It's not allowed.
It's not allowed?
I've decided we're going
to get away. Yeah?
Just me and you.
Australia.
And I've been to the Cunard
office and I got a magazine.
America's no good,
because that's where they are,
but there's no Italians in Australia.
I think there are, Mum.
Bad ones, I mean.
Have you stopped taking
those prison tablets?
- Don't you worry about me.
- I do.
Just you get better.
The doctor says it'll be five weeks.
Then, you'll be up and walking.
Now, there's a boat that leaves
on February the 13th.
Tell Tommy I need to see him.
Tell him to bring a gun small
enough to fit in the chamber pot,
- in case they come back.
- No, I've banned Tommy from coming.
Are the factories going
back to work tomorrow?
Just forget the fucking factories.
Is there any word of them
going out on strike?
We're going to Australia. It'll
just be you, me, and your sister.
Cos I've found out where she's buried -
it's somewhere outside Melbourne.
Listen, Mum.
I'm going to get better slowly...
...But you need to get better fast.
Without you, he falls apart,
and without him...
Without him, they'll take us all.
You've got to get us through this.
Then, I promise...
...I'll board that train with you
and we'll go to Australia.
I like your yard, Mr Strong.
How much would you take for it?
It's not for sale.
Not for sale?
Ok.
I just took a look round.
I like this place.
Fire for melting silver,
canal to get it away.
How much?
Nothing you see is for sale, Mr Gold.
Oh, everything is for sale.
Everything.
You tell Mr Strong
I'm going to buy his yard.
This yard has been in his
family since they settled.
But I have decided to make
it part of our deal.
Charlie?
Charlie, come here.
We're going to spin a coin
for your yard, Charlie.
You're going to what?
If it's heads,
Abby here takes all of this...
with my blessing.
Tommy.
And if it's tails...
...I fuck your daughter, Mr Gold.
You have three daughters, I hear...
...And Esmeralda is the eldest,
and also the prettiest,
so I'll have her.
So make her part of the deal
and spin her against the yard.
Tommy, for fuck sake.
Here, toss the coin, Mr Gold.
No.
Please don't believe this is a joke.
The coin to us is sacred. Yes, Arthur?
Sacred.
If you toss that coin, you
take a bet before witnesses.
And if I win...
Then, we'll insist that
the terms of this agreement,
the wager, are fulfilled.
Toss the coin, Mr Gold.
Tommy Shelby OBE...
...No wager today.
But with this penny, I will buy
a flower to put on your grave...
...When the time comes.
And before that time,
please don't again
disrespect my friends or
their valued property.
We missed Christmas - let's have it now.
Peace on earth, good will to all men.
Rum, Curly.
Toast to my brother, John.
Raise your glasses, all of you.
Raise 'em up, all of you.
- John Shelby.
- Cheers.
I got wire, I got chains,
I got steel rods - now what?
Right, put the steel rods
up the geese's arse there,
and then you put those
steel rods above the fire,
spinning the rod to stop
the bird from burning.
You did get potatoes, Charlie?
No, I didn't get fucking potatoes.
What's the matter with you?
I don't want that bastard, Aberama Gold,
putting it around that
we live like didicois.
I want him to see that we
live proper, that we eat proper,
in the proper way.
What the fuck are you talking about?
I'll get the potatoes meself.
Never thought my high-fucking-heels
from Paris would be stepping
through the horse shit
of Small Heath ever again.
Temporary, Polly.
Yeah, until hell freezes over.
How's Michael?
You said eight men from
New York, seven from Sicily,
at £500 each.
Of course, you can afford it.
Most, we'll do ourselves.
How many of your factories
are in the safe territories?
70%
70%.
Shelby Company Ltd will
continue to manufacture.
Lizzie says it's only whores these days.
Yeah.
Have them smuggled in, I suppose?
I need you back, Polly.
Paying whores for sex,
paying killers to kill...
Yeah - nothing for nothing.
Poor Thomas.
You know, our mother went this way -
spirits and ghosts, tablets,
fucking... fucking seances
scaring us kids halfway to fucking death.
Yeah, well, I'm not going that way.
Cos in the smoke, I realised something.
I'm just like you now,
you and Arthur.
I was dead in that noose,
and then I was saved.
So everything from now on is extra.
But what I didn't
understand until today...
Is when you're dead already...
You're free.
Fucking love it.
I'll help you, cos Michael
wants me to help you.
Starting now.
Get your whores vetted by Lizzie,
they'll use your weakness.
Don't take any new men on in
the factories unless
you know their families.
And your new friend,
Mr Aberama Gold...
He wants something other than just money.
I see things in the air around people,
it's not just the tablets.
It's real.
Ask him what he really wants.
She's a fine beast, this one.
Nothing you see is for sale, Mr Shelby.
Your grandfather camped
with mine for a while.
Yeah. That didn't last.
No, it ended badly...
In a pub called the Wenlock.
We were owed money. Still are.
Other than money and a scrapyard
that's clearly not for sale...
What is it that you want from me, Mr Gold?
How do you know I want anything from you?
Well, because my company treasurer
is a certified accountant,
and also, apparently, a witch.
You're a sporting man...
Yes, I am.
And a gambling man.
Bonnie, take off your shirt.
What I want from you, Mr Shelby,
is for you to take a gamble on him.
I want you to help my son
achieve his ambition.
What ambition might that be?
Who is it?
Inspector Moss.
I'm looking for Tommy.
He's at Charlie's.
But I wouldn't go there,
some bad men have arrived.
Yes, I've heard...
Be drunk by now... or worse.
Can you take a message?
The intelligence service
in London have sent seven officers
up to Birmingham to take
over the investigation
into the Communists and seditionists.
They've got a list of people
of great interest and, erm,
top of that list is
Ada Thorne, formerly Shelby.
Now, they seem to think that
she came back from New York
to organise the revolution in Birmingham.
Well, tell them they're wrong.
Ada Shelby's now firmly back
in place in the family business.
Thing is, when you get
a mark against your name,
it's very hard to shift it.
They will come looking for her.
Well, tell them there's a queue.
Everybody wants a Shelby.
Mrs Shelby...
These are military men,
no less dangerous than any Italians.
You tell Tommy.
I think he'll understand.
I'll say good night to you, then.
Hello, Curly.
- Oh, hello...
- I'm here to collect Mr Shelby's horse.
I'm a little early, I think.
A-Are you going to train
the horse to race?
Yes.
D-Don't use the crop,
she's very gentle.
I won't.
I-I...
How is Mr Shelby?
Well, now he's got
the Americans after him,
- he's a bit hard on people.
- The Americans?
Yeah, they call them the Mafia.
Dear God.
Yeah, there's 15 of them.
Yeah, they want to kill us all.
But we've got guns and
grenades and Aunt Polly's back,
so it's going to be OK. Yeah.
I-I'll get the horse.
Mr Shelby, thank God you're back.
We've got real trouble.
What meetings do I have today?
Erm, well, there's a supplier
from Coventry at ten,
the convenor of the
boilermakers union at 11,
and then Chamber of Commerce at one.
But that isn't the thing.
Right, clear a space here,
move this car back
and then 100 feet of rope and a bell.
- Rope?
- Yep, and a bell.
Mr Shelby, this place is about to explode.
Rope and a bell, Devlin. Ronnie, this way.
Yes, Mr Shelby.
Oh, by the way, the revolution's
scheduled to begin at noon.
Here he is - Billy Mills.
Former heavyweight champion,
Staffordshire, Warwickshire
and Worcestershire. Hello, Billy.
Yeah, and now I work for you, Mr Shelby,
for not enough money.
All right.
That enough for you?
- Enough for what?
- There's someone here wants to fight you.
Bonnie Gold! Come here, son.
I'm a heavyweight.
He's a welterweight, at best.
Nevertheless, he wants to fight you.
Yeah, and when I damage him,
the Blinders will take my eyes.
No comeback, Billy. It's just
a fight, Queensberry rules.
- When?
- Now.
- Where?
- Here.
Right, you lot, come here.
Let's make it interesting.
Come place a wager with me.
I'll give you good odds.
I'll give you good odds on the boy,
even better on the big lad.
£2, there you go. What you want?
Bonnie. Come here, son.
Your boy knows he can hit back, right?
I told him, in the professional game,
people want their money's worth.
Don't win too fast.
But if you've seen enough...
Finish it, Bonnie!
Fuck me. That was a punch.
What's he got, horseshoes
in those gloves, or what?
Nope. Just his dad's strength
and his mother's temper.
- Does he have fits?
- No.
- Asthma?
- How's he cut?
- No-one's cut him yet, but his skin's thick.
- Does he drink?
- Porter. Sometimes.
How many fights?
25 bare-knuckle, all knockouts,
five with gloves in pastures.
All knockouts.
Against Romany fighters?
That's why they won't let us
in the fairs no more
he keeps winning.
I could fight a fucking tree
and knock it out, Mr Shelby.
- I like him. I like...
- Mrs Eden's waiting upstairs.
All right, I'll be there
in a minute. Arthur.
Mr Shelby's on his way.
Fight in the workshop?
No. No, just a bit of sport.
Do you want more tea?
No. What kind of sport?
Sport between men, Mrs Eden.
Actually, I'm Miss Eden.
Be patient. A good man will come.
What do you think?
Don't know, it was over fast.
Yeah, but you can tell, aye?
I'll give him to the Irish boys
in Digbeth, they can teach him.
Yeah, and then what?
We promote him. Big money in London.
New York, if he's good.
We control him, run the book.
Control the odds. Like a horse.
Control when he wins, when he loses.
Alfie Solomons runs a fighter.
He says it's fucking money for nothing.
Fighting's been good for us,
better if we know who's going to win.
We've a lot going on, though, Tom.
Yeah. That's why it'd be good
to have the kid around.
If we take the fucking kid on,
one day he may end up
fucking taking a bullet for you.
Can't afford to lose
another brother, can I?
No horses like him, so he's all right.
Come on.
All right. We'll do it.
We need to do a deal about money.
Yeah. Speak to my accountant.
- The witch?
- The witch.
So when will be my first real
fight be, do you think, Mr Shelby?
Well, as soon as we can find men
stupid enough to get in the ring with you.
God help him.
There you go, Bonnie.
You're a Peaky Blinder now, son.
There you go.
The lion's share.
Thank you.
Mr Shelby, I understand
you've had a bereavement.
I'm here to talk business.
- Then I'll be blunt.
- And as will I.
What you're doing here is robbery.
Every man is free to leave.
You cut five shillings
from the weekly wage.
And you said, if I did that,
you'd bring every man and women
in all my factories out on strike.
Yes.
Do you have a whistle?
If so, blow it.
I thought at least we
might have a discussion,
as I do with other owners.
I'm not other owners.
No.
You believe because coal is expensive
and it's been a cold winter,
and because wages have been
cut over these past 12 months,
you think cos of all that
nobody will walk out on strike,
cos no-one can afford to.
And, until recently,
that would have been true.
But something has changed this past year.
A cold wind from the East.
People are not afraid any more.
I have it on very good authority
that the Bolsheviks couldn't
organise a fucking picnic.
You know, Mr Shelby,
it's almost as if you want trouble.
If the rule of law in Birmingham
were to break down during
this... period of turmoil
for my family, then, yes,
that would indeed have its benefits...
..For reasons you could not understand.
I've heard rumours.
Sport between men.
Just blow your fucking whistle, eh?
Tools down, we got to clear it...
Right, come on, you lot,
put your tools down. We're outside.
Go on.
Just leave it.
Just leave it, let's get out.
Everyone out.
I said, everyone out.
Stop working, immediately.
Yeah, come in.
I did say this would happen.
Who's next?
he's a delegate from the
European Council for Trade.
He's here to talk about the
import of car parts to France.
Right.
He's come all the way from Paris.
But, given the circumstances,
I can send him away.
Given what circumstances? Send him in.
Mr Shelby, this is
Monsieur Paz, from Paris.
I heard you had trouble.
It's good of you to see me.
You just came from Paris, eh?
You know Paris?
I left Paris in a cattle truck.
They said you were French.
No, I came here from Paris...
..That does not mean I'm French.
Guess where I'm from.
Well, in my cattle truck in Paris...
..There were American soldiers.
We played cards.
They sound like you.
Did you win?
You didn't come on a train.
Your suit is pressed,
your shoes are clean.
Where do you get your suits made?
I have a tailor...
..In New York City.
Look...
Fenacci. Italian.
He's my uncle.
He makes suits in a
basement in Mott Street.
He is my uncle, so every
stitch is stitched with blood.
I heard you dress well, Mr Shelby.
But now I see...
..Not so well as me.
You know, I have uncles as well...
..But they're not the sort
of men who would, uh...
..Who would work in a basement
with a needle and thread...
..Mr Changretta.
I am surprised how easy it was
to get into a room with you.
And now?
And now...
And now you should know
that during the trouble
you had earlier on your factory floor,
I sent an accomplice
into your office in overalls.
He found your gun...
..And unloaded it.
Arthur Shelby...
..Polly Gray....
..Michael Gray...
..John Shelby...
..Spent.
Ada Thorne...
..And, finally...
..Tommy Shelby.
None of you will survive.
Your level of security is pitiful...
..And we are an organisation
of a different dimension.
I could have killed you
when I walked through the door.
But, you see...
..I want you to be the last.
I want you to be alive
after your entire family is dead...
..Cos my mother says
that is what'll hurt you the most.
You people have traditions
of honour. As do we.
Instead of sending you a black hand,
I could have had you killed
in the night without knowing why.
But I want you to know why.
And I want to suggest to you
that we fight this vendetta with honour.
No civilians. No children.
No police.
Welcome to Birmingham, Mr Changretta.
Grazie.
That smell. I'll miss it.
What, the shit house?
Nah.
I don't know what it is.
Birmingham, I suppose.
Small Heath.
That smell.
The smell brings it back.
Where's John, do you think, Tom?
Fuck knows.
He's gone, though,
like a hole behind your head.
I thought you thought there was a heaven.
No.
More like hell for our John.
Nah, neither one.
He's just not here any more.
It's like with Grace.
Arthur...they're just gone.
Just fucking gone.